visitwales.com 2013-06-09

# Privacy & Cookie Policy

Visit Wales and the Welsh Government, respect and wish to protect the privacy of the users of our services.   
This document sets out the details of our privacy & cookie policy in relation to information collected on this website. 

## Website Analytics

We use a web analytics tool to enhance content provided on site and to analyse site usage;   
how users arrive at our site, what they do on the site, what browser they are using and on what operating system etc.   
This tool is Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. ('Google').   
Google Analytics uses 'cookies' and JavaScript code to help analyse user activity on websites.   
The information generated about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored on Google servers in the United States. However, this analytics data, is not tied to personally identifiable information. 

Google will not associate your IP address with any other data previously held. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

Read [Google's Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) and [Google's Terms of Service](http://www.google.com/policies/terms/) for detailed information. 

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, to find out how to do this go to [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)

## Cookies

**Firstly, none of our cookies capture or use personal information.**

We use a number of different cookies on our site. If you do not know what cookies are, or how to control or delete them, then we recommend you visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) for detailed guidance. 

We currently operate an ‘implied consent’ policy which means that by visiting this site, we assume you are happy with this usage.   
If you are not happy, then you should either not use this site in future, delete Visit Wales cookies having visited the site,   
or you should browse the site using your browser’s anonymous usage setting (called “Incognito” in Chrome, “InPrivate” for Internet Explorer, "Private Browsing" in Firefox and Safari etc.) 

The table below describe the cookies we use on this site and what we use them for. 

**PHP Session ID** | Our Content Management System (Amaxus) uses this cookie to maintain your computer's session to its server. The information is not shared or sold to third party organisations for any purpose, is a randomly generated characters and does not contain personal information.   
  
---|---  
**AMAXHOST** | Our Content Management System (Amaxus) uses this cookie to maintain your computer's session to its server. The information is not shared or sold to third party organisations for any purpose, is an IP address and does not contain personal information.   
  
**GFK Survey Referer** | You may have been shown a pop up survey when you entered our site, we use this cookie to ensure we don't show you this again and to detect which website you were refered from to ours. The information is not shared or sold to third party organisations for any purpose, is the URL of the last webpage you visited and does not contain personal information.   
  
**Google Analytics** | We use these cookies to understand how the site is being used in order to improve the user experience. The information is shared with Google only for these purposes, is a randomly generated number and does not contain personal information.   
  
**GroupM - mookie1.com & gmads.net** | We use these cookies to count and track users who have clicked on Visit Wales advertising or promotional content on other sites that links to this site. The information is not shared or sold to third party organisations for any purpose, is randomly generated characters and does not contain personal information.   
  
**Quantserve** | We use these cookies to count and track users who have clicked on Visit Wales advertising or promotional content on other sites that links to this site. The information is not shared or sold to third party organisations for any purpose, is randomly generated characters and does not contain personal information.   

### External web services

We use a number of external web services on the Visit Wales, mostly to display content within our web pages.   
For example, to display images we often use Flickr; to show eBrochures we use Issuu; to show videos we use Vimeo and YouTube. This is not an exhaustive or complete list of the services we use, or might use in the future, when embedding content, but these are the most common. We cannot prevent these sites, or external domains, from collecting information on your usage of this embedded content. If you are not logged in to these external services then they will not know who you are but are likely to gather anonymous usage information e.g. number of views, plays, loads etc. 

### Surveys & Competitions

We sometimes request information from users via surveys, competitions or for a particular users services (e.g. newsletter registration). Participation in these surveys or competitions is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested will include contact information (as supplied to the site during newsletter registration) and supplementary information on your opinions and preferences. We will use the contact information to notify winners. We will not publish winners' details on the site though on request we will provide details of any winner's name and organisation. If the survey or contest has a sponsor then we may share information given by entrants with the sponsor, but only with the user's consent. 

## The Data Protection Act

Under the Data Protection Act, we have a legal duty to protect any information we collect from you. We use leading technologies and encryption software to safeguard your data, and keep strict security standards to prevent any unauthorised access to it. 

We do not pass on your details to any third party or other government department. 

Access to your information and contacting us   
If you wish to see our records of any correspondence you have sent to us, or if you have a query or complaint about this privacy policy or about the site, you can contact us at: [info@visitwales.co.uk](mailto:info@visitwales.co.uk)

If you have any comments on our privacy policy as set out in this document, please contact us using the following email address: [info@visitwales.co.uk](mailto:info@visitwales.co.uk)

## When and how do we collect data from you?   

### We collect personal data from you:- 

i. when you order brochures from the Site (directly or through VisitWales);   
ii. when you register on the Site that you are happy for us to send information to you in the future.   
iii. when you enter a competition or prize draw.   

## What data is collected? 

The data we collect may be personal data and may include your name, email address, postal address and postcode.   
We may also ask for your telephone number to enable us to contact you if you have won a prize draw or competition. 

We are required by HM Customs and Excise to store and collect information about the country you live in. 

## Who collects the information? 

The information is collected by us, Welsh Government, Cardiff Bay, Cardiff, CF99 1NA. 

We hold valid notifications under the Data Protection Act 1998. 

The personally identifiable information that is required to use the Site is owned solely by us. We do not share, sell or rent your information to any other person, company or organisation in any way other than as disclosed in this document or as stated at the point where the information is collected. You should, however, note that if you request a brochure through the Site or VisitWales, in some instances your details may be forwarded to a regional tourism marketing organisation so that they can despatch the brochure to you. [Your details will only be used by that organisation for the purposes of sending the brochure to you.] 

## Consent

By disclosing personal information to us you consent to the collection, storage and processing of information in the manner described in this Policy. 

## How is the information used and by whom? 

The above information will be used by us for the following purposes only: - 

  * To send you promotional email. 

From time to time, we may send a newsletter to your email address. This would contain information on new features and services in relation to the Site.   
The information may also be made available to companies of tourism related specialist supplies, products and services who are interested in advertising on the Site and who may, from time to time, email you details of specialist services which may be of interest to you. 

We are not in favour of our users being inundated with inappropriate and unsolicited email. We will therefore carefully select the organisations to whom we would provide such data. Further, we will not, in any event, provide such companies with any of your financial information. 

You also have the right to 'opt-out' of your information being used for purposes not directly related to the Site. For further details of this right, please see 'Your Rights in Relation to this Information' below. 

## What security measures do we have in place to protect this information? 

To protect your privacy, your financial information is sent to us through a secure server which encrypts it before it is sent to us. We also use our best efforts to protect your information offline: it is only given to those of our employees who genuinely need to have access to it in order to perform their job.   
Furthermore, our security procedures for storing and disclosing customer details conform with the Data Protection Act 1998 so as to prevent unauthorised access to it. 

The Site may, from time to time, contain links to other web sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of the owners and operators of these sites. We therefore encourage you to read the privacy statements and policies on each site to which you are asked to submit personal information. 

## Your rights in relations to this information

If you wish to change any of your personal information, please contact us on the below email address.   
You also have the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your information used for purposes not directly related to the Site at the point where we ask you for that information. For example, if you wish to enter a competition but do not want to receive future newsletters, promotional emails or marketing material, simply leave the relevant box that appears in our registration form unticked.   
If, after a certain period of time, you decide that you no longer wish to receive newsletters, promotional and marketing emails, you can unsubscribe directly through the email communication or contact us and request removal from the database.   
Please note, however, that we cannot backdate any changes that you make. This means that you could continue to receive information from any third party you have consented to contact you, where we have provided your details to that third party. You will therefore have to contact each such third party if you no longer wish to receive newsletters, promotional and marketing emails directly from them. 

## Policy Change

If this privacy policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties.

## Questions

If you have any questions about this document or our procedures please contact us at [info@visitwales.co.uk](mailto:info@visitwales.co.uk)

## Are you really looking for Cookies?

We don't really make cookies in Wales, we much prefer Welsh Cakes.   
To find out how to make these delicious little treats, go to our [Traditional Recipes page](http://www.visitwales.co.uk/about-wales-guide-to-wales-culture-people-and-language/food/welsh-recipes/welsh-recipes/).
